Hello, I'm teaching Elder Derek Radney,
pastor at Trinity Church in Winston
Salem, North Carolina, and I'm hosting
this conversation today on behalf of the
Alliance for Mission and Renewal. The
Alliance exists to help foster a
unified, faithful, and flourishing PCA.
And you can go to a4MR.org to learn more
about who we are and what we're working
for within the PCA and how to get
involved. One of the things that AMR um
wants to facilitate is uh healthy
dialogue amidst disagreement and uh and
also productive churchmanship. And
that's why I'm hosting this conversation
today on overture 27 which was answered
in the affirmative as amended by the
general assembly in Louisville uh just
here recently in June and which will be
sent to the presbyteries for advice and
consent this year. This overture
addresses BCO34-1,
which is a chapter that many have
attempted to revise or fix for decades.
And the two men that I'm speaking with
today, along with many others, have had
different ideas about how to fix this
part of the BCO. And so this
conversation uh really comes on the back
end of decades of healthy debate uh
disagreement, conviction, and ultimately
compromise which I hope can be a model
for the PCA going forward and how we
address all sorts of issues. So let me
introduce our guests uh even though I'm
sure that uh many of you are familiar
with both of them uh since they've both
served as moderators of our general
assembly in recent years. Um, first we
have ruling Elder Mel Duncan, uh, the
church administrator of Second
Presbyterian Church in Greenville, South
Carolina, uh, where he teaches Sunday
school. And Mel also serves as the
stated clerk of Calvary Presbyter, and
he served as the moderator for the 53rd
PCA uh, General Assembly this June. Uh,
Mel is married uh, to Linda, a classical
orchestral musician, and they have three
children. Uh, also with us we have uh,
ruling elder Howie Dono who's from Boise
Presbyterian Church in Boise, Idaho.
He's been a PCA member for 44 years and
served as a ruling elder in five
churches, four mission churches in four
different presbyteries. And he served as
the 47th General Assembly moderator in
Dallas and he's been on the SJC for
about 28 years now. He was a pilot in
the Air Force then with American
Airlines. He's been married for 41 years
and has three daughters and two sons and
12 grandchildren. So, uh I'm sure a lot
more could be said about both of you,
but I want to thank you both uh for
joining me today uh and uh and joining
all of us. So, what we're going to do
here is jump right into kind of talking
about overture 27.
Um, you know, I was not on overtures
this year, but I did uh I did sit in on
the overtures committee and one of the
overures sent by Westminster Presbyter
uh was amended by the overures
committee. And then if I remember
correctly, both you uh Mel and Howie
spoke in favor of the overture as
amended. And if my memory serves me
correctly, Mel, you said that your kind
of position on this had changed and you
found that this was now an acceptable
way to fix a long uh a long-term
problem. Uh then it went to the floor
from the over recommendation and there
was some opposition to it. Uh and and in
full transparency, I briefly spoke in
favor of it largely just to defer to you
guys because I saw that you guys had
been working on this and I knew from
some past years some of the work that
had been done. Uh, I know there were
conversations with Fred Greco and David
Coffin and others as well. So, I just
want to say, hey, this is a
long-standing issue. Uh, so I spoke, you
know, in favor of the committee's
recommendation, but really um it was the
committee chairman um Guy Waters um who
gave kind of the committee's rationale
which seemed to win the day in terms of
the general assembly. So, it was
answered in the affirmative as amended.
So, with all that sort of uh throat
clearing, let me turn it over to you
guys. I'm going to start with you,
Howie, and let you just kind of talk
about the history of this issue. And
Mel, you feel free to jump in and add
some more to that if you would.
>> Sure.
>> Sure. There's there's history in the PCA
and there's also history in the PC
uh USA. Um 341 is a provision that would
allow a higher court to assume original
jurisdiction over a member of the lower
court or a member under the jurisdiction
of the lower court.
Um and it shouldn't be done easily
because the we respect the lower courts
but sometimes there's a situation where
the lower court
hasn't handled a matter hasn't handled
allegations
uh in a way that the broader church
deems to be the best way. So 341
provides an avenue uh for situations
like that. uh at present
uh it says the lower court has to refuse
to act. So that's one of the triggers
and the other is a a threshold of uh how
many uh presbyteries need to petition
the assembly for assumption of original
jurisdiction.
Uh so it currently says if the
presbyterary refuses to act in doctrinal
cases or case of public scandal and two
other presbyteries requests the assembly
to assume original jurisdiction, the
assembly shall do so. And there is a um
SJC manual chapter 16 which provides
what the SJC will do if it assumes
original jurisdiction. uh several
paragraphs on how the allegation should
be investigated and then uh how the
parties brief it and then eventually how
the SGC would conduct a trial if it
deemed it necessary. Um
so going back to the John Wood case,
there was a case in Tennessee Valley
Presbyterian
and a minister allegedly had a woman uh
preach twice on Sunday nights. Um they
argued that
>> 1999ish, is that right?
>> Yes. Okay. Yeah. It was the case was uh
it was called the John Wood matter case
99-01.
Um the SJC ruled
it was a petition from Western Carolina
Presbyter
I believe and the SJC ruled it out of
order saying that the session is the one
that controls that not the minister.
um was a 17-3 vote and I was one of the
three that dissented in that vote. I
think it might have been the first year
I was on. Uh and then the year after
that there were um well, let me back up.
the 2000
uh GA in Tampa.
Um the um over committee
uh persuaded the assembly to refer it
back to the SJC to conduct the 312
investigation. This was before the SJC
manual had any
um provisions for how to do a 341.
and the SJC
uh there was a three judge panel that
went to Tennessee Valley and
investigated. I think Dr. Aquilla was
chairing that threeman panel and the SJC
ruled that there was no strong
presumption of guilt. So there was no
indictment.
And then in the in 2002, the Birmingham
Assembly, there were 24 presbyteries
over the assembly to change the
threshold uh to 10% of the presbyteries
have to petition and uh that passed the
Birmingham assembly, but it failed in
the presbyteries by a 40 to 24 vote. It
needed 43 to pass. So that was one
attempt to by overture to change 341.
And then a few years later in Dallas,
uh, Reverend Steve Wilkins was in
Louisiana area and, um, I don't remember
which presbyterary
uh, sent
to uh, the SJC asking for the SJC to
assume original jurisdiction. The SJC
ruled that Louisiana Presbyter had not
refused to act, that they had acted in
some way. Um, I was disqualified from
that case because I was in Central
Carolina and Central Carolina sent a
>> something at the time that was called a
memorial
>> u asking it was kind of like a 40-5 sort
of thing asking the
>> so I was disqualified um in that um and
the SACE acted on Central Carolina's
uh 40-5 and cited Louisiana Presbyter to
appear at a trial. Uh Louisiana Press
Drake pleaded guilty to one of the
charges and was convicted to the other
and was admonished. And then a year
after that, um Central Carolina filed an
overture seeking to change 341 again
because the SJC had said Louisiana
Presbyter didn't refuse to act. So, uh
we tried in Central Carolina to send it
up and uh to strike to simply strike
refuses to act. just get it even get it
out of the paragraph and it just bumped
the threshold to five and that didn't
make it out of the uh 2009 Orlando
assembly. So, um we're still trying to
fix 341. Um
>> Derek, um you know, some of us use Gro
or Wikipedia in the PCA, we just go to
Howie.
>> Uh you're you're experiencing Howedia
and let me just say it's so good to be
with you. It it's it's wonderful to be a
part of the podcast with you today. Uh
and let me just say greetings to 47 from
53. Hope you're having a good day out in
um [laughter]
Howie's done a remarkable job I think of
setting the recent kind of judicial and
legislative history of of 40 of 341. Uh
this is broadly speaking the idea of a
denomination.
It's really kind of like if you want to
go big picture, it's almost like
Marberry versus Madison. It's like
judicial review. It's how does a
denomination
on the great matters before the GA. And
I'm not talking about small matters. I'm
talking about break in case of
constitutional emergency. I wish we
could almost say this can only be used
once a decade uh in the language
somewhere because really in my lifetime
I think I was thinking about this this
morning. There's probably only been
three times in my view where this has
properly been before uh the denomination
as an item that I would be comfortable
with it being applied. Uh but that being
said, this um this matter has a recent
history which Howie has laid out for you
pretty well. Um but it also has a deeper
history and part of that deeper history
is in uh the way the PCA came into
being. Uh the PCA, you always have to
remember the PCA is formed in reaction
to a denomination that was top down,
that was heavy-handed, that was highly
centralized, that the judicatories were
used really were weaponized by uh
modernist and and folks who were who
were not uh theologically evang
evangelicals or that they were deeply
committed to being not uh reformed and
and Westminster people. And so part of
our um of our denominational polity is
that we were not going to allow a
denominational agency committee
structure to be top down. And that even
goes into the the book of church order.
And so, uh, when I think about BCO341, I
actually think back a 100red years ago
to the fundamentalist modernist
controversy in the PCUs in which
conservatives in the Carolas complained
against ET Thompson, who was a legendary
Union Seminary professor who was
promoting higher criticism at Union
Seminary and who uh was charged uh with
heresy. and the peaceuous version of the
of this um part of the book of church
order that we now call 341 was used to
bring him up on charges and he was
acquitted uh and it he was acquitted
largely on the idea that his presbyter
uh said that he was not a heretic and
the denomination therefore said because
of that we're not going to reach in and
say that east handover Presbyter
in another case Meckllinburgg Presbyter
uh we're not going to overturn that. And
so when the PCA is formed, uh there are
all kind of conversations about how are
we going to be different from the PCUs?
How are we going to allow the
denomination to have safeguards? What
are the boundaries going to be? And so
there's a conversation at the beginning
from founders and uh when when you think
about the great polity-minded folks, you
think about Jack Williamson, you think
about Bob Canada, you think about Dr.
Smith and there was a recognition that
there needed to be some kind of a of a
robust 341.
And when you go, for example, to the PCA
history center BCO project, which is a
great resource for A4MR folks to look
at, you can actually see the legislative
history of BCO341 and how the language
has changed over the years and how we've
gotten to where we are now. And so where
we are now is this language of failure
to act which Howie and I are going to
dialogue about how that's just very
amorphous language which is very hard to
apply and has never been successfully
applied before the SJC. And then we're
going to talk about the standard by
which it needs to be applied. And that's
a conversation that really Howy and I
have been talking about for a decade
really if you think about it.
>> Yeah. Um so so I would say you know both
the recent history of this and the and
the old history of this is important to
understanding why this is such a big
deal. Uh this is a big deal because the
PCA needs to have a mechanism in that
rare once in a decade, maybe even once
in a generation case in which there's a
theological crisis that is uh so
brimming that a presbyterary really
can't handle it for whatever reason. And
so that's why this is an important
issue. And that's why Mel and Howy are
talking to Derek. uh you know it it may
be surprising to some of your uh
listeners or viewers that Mel and Howie
talk all the time with one another uh
that we we actually do agree on one or
two things and this is something that
we've come to recognize is something
that we really believe will make the PCA
better if we could fix this and we
believe it needs the language needs to
be fixed but that the standard by which
that the language would be applied side
needs to be made more difficult so that
it would be used very carefully and
deliberatively uh by the PCA as a whole.
Howie, does that sound fairer the way I
laid that out?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'm I'm uh I've not been around as
long as you guys have in the PCA, but I
mean I think I can actually think of two
situations in the in the last 6 years
where I've heard people raise the issue
of is this a 34-1 situation where where
a presbyterary seems to maybe not be
handling a teaching elder properly and
do other presbyteries want to try to
come in and and move that original
jurisdiction to the general assembly.
And I think regardless of where you are
in the PCA, you can think of situations
where you'd want a particular
presbyterary to to kind of um have a
matter taken up by the GA, right? And so
we need a functional workable way to do
that. That's also going to avoid, I
think, like you said, Howie, u it being
very easy to do because you don't want
just, you know, any issue to get pulled
by the general assembly, but you also
need a clear mechanism by which uh it
can actually happen. So maybe I'm
jumping ahead, but
>> No, I actually think that's a great
point. And Howie, that might actually be
a a point or a placeholder for you to
remind us all why the SJC doesn't meddle
in cases locally. Why does why doesn't
the SJC deal with the merits of cases
that come to it? Why does it always seem
like the SJC is just dealing with
process sin?
Well, we have to deal with process, but
we do deal with merits, too. Um, it kind
of depends on the case. In in a
situation like the one we're talking
about where a presbyterary declines to
indict for whatever reason, um, the only
way that could come to uh, the SJC is
via a complaint against a
non-indictment, which is an awkward
procedural thing. Uh we had one recently
that was um quite difficult to work
through a complaint against a
non-indictment. Whereas a 341
uh if a presbyterary declined to indict
or did not indict did not find a strong
presumption of guilt, that's clearly a
fact that's easily determined. And then
if the threshold is met then it triggers
uh SJC manual chapter 16 and the
procedures for assuming original
jurisdiction. Um
it is far simpler than what we have now.
Um and it would work a lot better than a
complaint against the non-indictment
which could take as we saw recently a
couple years to adjudicate.
Uh, and it's not the best way to
adjudicate a non-indictment. The 341
route would be a better way and the
cleaner way, a more efficient way, and
probably produce a better decision.
>> Why do you think it's important that the
PCA needs to change this? What why why
are you animated about this? Well,
partly because I've seen the old 341 try
to be applied in the Wood case, uh, the
Wilkins case. Um, it could have been
applied in a recent case out of a
Presbyterian in the central part of the
US. Uh, and it would have handled those
three things a whole lot better than,
uh, the complaint avenue. So, and I
agree, it's a once in a decade. I expect
once in a decade there's going to be a a
presbyterary that decides it doesn't
think a man should be indicted when
17 18 19 other presbyteries think he
probably should be and you punt that to
the SJC and then let them investigate
and decide.
>> Yeah. So maybe you could just really
quick get into specifically what would
this process look like if this passes
just be very specific. How would these
presbyteries,
>> you know, um grab jurisdiction? How
would that happen?
>> Okay, so let's say in my presbyter
um somebody was um preach a sermon on
something that was deemed by others to
be not uh orthodox
um and word gets around on the internet
or whatever and um it's a doctrinal
case. Uh
>> let's have fun with it, Howie. Let's say
it's a non-trinitarian sermon. Let's
just send let's just sin boldly, shall
we?
>> Sure. Sure. Right. So, um, word gets
around and if this overture passes, if
the preseries and the Milwaukee Assembly
adopt it, um, then our presetary,
we do an investigation. We say, uh,
we're fine with that. He's there's no
reason to indict that guy.
And um
then if 20% of the presbyteries
send a one-s sentence email to the
stated clerk, uh Dr. Greco, we believe
that
we request that the assembly assume
original jurisdiction over Reverend John
Smith of Pacific Northwest Presbyter
because of uh sermons that he's been
preaching on the Trinity. Um
and the clerk doesn't have to make any
determination as long as once he gets
the the last presbyterary necessary to
meet that threshold. Uh he sends it to
the SJC and then SJC chapter 16. Uh the
first thing that's done is
a panel is appointed to decide or to
determine whether the case is in order.
And if it's determined it's in order,
the panel conducts an investigation of
the allegations. Uh the panel
uh produces a report. Uh the report is
sent to the accused minister as well as
the petitioning presbyteries and then
the SJC
uh considers the panel's recommendation
which would either be to indict or not
indict.
the parties can file the briefs and then
the SJC
uh hears the report of that
investigative panel and decides there is
no strong presumption of guilt or there
is and then the SJC proceeds to a
regular trial. So um the SJC panel does
an investigation
which would be talk all kinds of listen
to the sermons, talk to witnesses, talk
to people from petitioning presbyteries.
There's lots of different ways to do an
investigation, which the SJC can't do
that kind of stuff if it just comes up
as a complaint against a non-indictment.
>> Yeah. So, this would go straight to the
SJC in this case based on motions passed
by a certain number of presbyteries and
sent to the clerk. Clerk would send it
to the SGC. So, we're not waiting for
the next general assembly to have to
take this up as a it goes straight to
the SJC,
>> right? It would be, you know, like I
said, a one-s sentence email from, let's
say, 17 or 18 presbyteries
and um all they have to say is there was
no indictment and we petitioned for
assumption of original jurisdiction.
They don't have to presence.
They don't have to do anything. It's
just we're filing a petition for AOJ and
the clerk sends it to the SJC and
>> and they takes [clears throat] it from
there.
>> Yeah. Okay. as soon as as soon as the
18th presbyary files the email or
whatever the
>> Yeah, Mel, what were you going to add?
>> Well, I was going to say Howie, some of
our friends at GA who spoke against this
did not like the linking of uh failure
to indict with finding no strong
presumption of a guilt. But I actually
think there's a logic to that. I mean,
it shows that the presbyterary did its
due diligence, did some judicial work,
and then another presbyterary would have
a clear basis to say there was no
indictment because there was some
judicial process that did not result in
an indictment. Is is that the logic of
the new language there in 341?
>> Right. The new language replaces refuses
to act with the with this phrase finds
no strong presumption of guilt or
otherwise declines to indict. So um they
could either ignore it which is
declining to indict or they could
investigate and find no strong
presumption of guilt. But the
petitioning presbyterary doesn't have to
even communicate with the
alleged delinquent presbyter. They just
have to listen to the sermon, uh,
realize he's not been indicted, and then
they file their one-s sentence email to
Dr. Greco.
>> Yeah.
>> And and the language also includes a
percentage of presbyteries rather than
just a number. And that's that's the
wisdom of that I'm I'm thinking was as
we grow or shrink presbyaries,
um, we don't want that ratio to get all
uh messed up, right? So the the
percentage
>> just in just index it to the number of
presbyteries so that it's a constant as
the PCA grows there'll be a constant
threshold that grows with it. Um, and
and that's actually a conversation that
I don't I hate to admit this on the A4MR
podcast, but Howie has won me over on
this that part of the of the need for
this is building trust in the PCA. And
part of that is raising the bar so that
all parts of the house will know that
we're going to do this carefully,
deliberatively. We're not going to just
smash and grab this every time someone
is upset. Uh I I was a I've been a clerk
now for about 15 years and it's very you
know my first month clerking a
presbyterary
uh you know everything is a four alarm
fire and everything needs to be dealt
with uh that no the 341 is a is a once
in a decade type of thing in the life of
the church and so there needs to be
extraordinary measures for when you
utilize it and part of that is is is
frankly a a a gentleman's agreement
between different parts of the PCA that
there's going to be a high standard by
which this threshold is met in which you
do this. And I I frankly would like that
number to be lower, but I think the
number needs to be 20% for the PCA to go
along and use this. And so I'm happy to
advocate for this for the greater good.
And I think the threshold is where it
needs to be partly because I think it's
the only way it passes 58 presbyaries.
>> I I have friends and acquaintances that
uh don't like assumption of original
jurisdiction philosophically
and they certainly didn't like two or
three presbyteries being able to trigger
it. Um so
um it's tough to get an overture passed
through twothirds of the presbyteries
um if it's controversial.
Um and I know I'm reasonably sure well
we tried 10% and it didn't work but
those were the
>> that was just a few years ago right?
Like that was 2022 or so.
>> Yeah. Well, 2002 was the first time it
was tried at 10%.
And that was um yeah, that didn't pass.
Um
so
20% was just kind of a stab at what do I
think
twothirds of the pressaries will will
pass.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's basically a balancing
act. Like it it can't be impossible to
to to get original jurisdiction. There's
there's just cases where everyone would
admit something's got to be done here.
We got to intervene. Uh but if you set
it too low, it makes a lot of people
nervous because they feel like folks are
going to constantly be jumping in trying
to grab hold of stuff. So it it's just
that's the been the balance balancing
act,
>> right? And the once in a decade thing
that Mel alluded to, um those types of
situations,
there's going to be 181 19 presbyteries
filing one sentence emails. Um,
I have no doubt about that.
>> All right. Do you guys have any thoughts
on on maybe what are some objections
that might get raised? We're already
touching on some of that, but what what
do you anticipate or what have you heard
in terms of people that oppose this or
at least might oppose this?
Um, one thing I think it's
um understand an understandable
objection, but I don't think it
um well,
the objection is that if you require 20%
of the presbyteries, then there's going
to be a lot of dialogue going back and
forth talking about someone's alleged
sins.
And and that's true, but it's going to
be on the internet anyway. Uh so I don't
think there's any way to keep something
keep a lid on something. Um yeah, the
first you know I mean I would assume
that somebody that's bothered by what a
particular presbyter has done uh in
handling allegations will contact a
friend in another presbyterian and say
hey you think you could get your
presbyter to uh file a petition for
assumption of original jurisdiction. I
don't think that's I don't I don't have
a problem with that. Um that's the way
it's going to happen and uh frankly
maybe it'll keep keep the stuff off the
internet
more than increase the amount of it on
the internet if you know that hey
there's a way to do this without
blogging about it.
>> Yeah. Mel
>> Derek, some of my friends are worried
that we've not we've not found the right
language quite yet to replace failure to
act. They're concerned that, you know,
the SJC may take this language and do
the same thing with the with failure to
act with with this new language. And I I
I disagree with that, but I I you can't
really tell how the SJC is going to do
anything necessarily, but I do think
this language is an improvement. Um, I
also think that the SJC, if it received
a uh 341 petition
from 20 presbyteries in the PCA, would
probably consider it very carefully in a
way that it might not from say two or
three presbyteries.
>> And so I think if there was a I mean I I
don't want to relitigate any matters
from the last 20 years, but let's just
go back to the wood matter. I I think if
20 PCA Presbyteries sent the John Wood
matter to the SJC,
I think that they might have looked at
that a little different than they would
have just with two Presbyteries sending
it to the SJC. Uh partly because I think
20 presbyteries weighing in on a matter
is a pretty significant statement of
concern. So, uh yeah, I think there's
some concern. I mean, Derek, how many
times have we seen this in the PCA? Do
we tweak the RAO or do we tweak the BCO?
Do we make it really narrow or do we
keep it broad so that there's, you know,
freedom to interpret? There's a
balancing act with that. My position is
Howie has made the language better. Uh,
and I think we need to make it better
and see if it works is my position.
Yeah.
All right. Well, um, is there anything
we're missing to kind of unpack this
issue and and give some Presbyterian
some understanding of what this is all
about before they go to vote on this in
the upcoming year?
I know that the author of Westminster
because um had some concerns about
um private matters because the phrasing
the phrasing that's already in the book
uh is doctrinal cases or cases of public
scandal. And he said, "Well, then you
you're insulating a a private scandal, a
private matter. You can't assume
original jurisdiction over that." And I
can understand that to a point, but
if it's heinous enough, uh it's very
likely going to become pretty public
scandal in short order. So,
>> uh if I get if I get arrested tomorrow,
I'm guessing somebody's going to know
about it in the PCA.
>> Yeah. You know, Derek, I would say um we
as a denomination, we tend to focus on
the grand matters of discipline because
they're scandalous in nature and they
draw attention and their conversation
matters. Uh as a general rule, anytime
we can talk about ordinary regular
uh both positive and negative, you know,
church discipline, just regular church
discipline, it's a good thing for PCA
churches to do. I mean, I when I get my
PCA statistical things, I'm always just
curious to see if local PCA churches are
doing any kind of discipline.
>> And so, I would hope that this
discussion, while I think it's important
to remember from time to time, there are
grand matters that draw the entire
denomination's
attention to a doctrinal matter or what
may be a public scandal. I think the
important thing is that every PCA church
needs to be carefully
uh shephering and weeding its roles. It
needs to be lovingly working through
marriage and divorce matters. It needs
to be doing the hard work of church
discipline which sometimes involves um
applying the censures that that the Lord
has given to the PCA to use. And uh in
the grand matters, we do need to be
prepared to do 341, but I hope in the
little matters, I hope we're doing the
day-to-day work of church discipline in
the PCA as well.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's just like with
pastoring, the more you're doing the
positive side of discipline, the you
know, right worship and teaching and the
the whole form of government, uh the
less often you have to do the corrective
and discipline, uh judicial process, but
but sometimes we have to do it and we
need to make sure we have good
mechanisms for that. Um, I do want to
say that we did invite some folks who
had a different view on this matter to
join us in this conversation and they
weren't quite ready to to speak to the
issues. Uh, that that is important at
AMR that we give everybody a voice and
we model, you know, charitable
disagreement. Uh, in this case, you guys
both support this change and we I
thought it was beneficial just because
you haven't always been on the same side
of this to have you guys talk. Um, but
in the future, we'll always want to try
to invite more u dialogue across
disagreement. But I really appreciate
you guys taking time to uh to share with
us your thoughts on this and I'm really
thankful for um how you you've
diligently contended over the years uh
up to this point and that you're now
kind of modeling how we can hopefully
come to something that's workable that
everybody can be content with. you know,
because I think a lot more of the BCO
changes that that we need to propose are
going to are going to need to be things
that we've been working through together
over a period of time until we've come
to a place where there's there's a sort
of broad wisdom on the issue. So, thank
you guys for modeling that and thanks
for your time. Any any last words?
Yeah, our sister denominations have
these. ARP has it. Uh RPCNA has it. EPC
even has it. Um, but all of theirs are
vague also, like our original one. Um,
so we're going to be leading the pack in
making this clear and simple and maybe
they'll follow.
>> Yeah. Or maybe they'll learn from our
mistake. Go ahead, Mel.
>> We'll see. We'll see.
>> Well, I uh I'm I'm confident that that
this is the right step forward and I've
enjoyed talking with Howie about it.
It's been fun to be on the program
today, Derek. Thanks for having me.
>> All right. Well, thank you, Mr.
Moderator and Mr. Moderator for y'all's
time. Uh thanks for everyone who tuned
in and uh stay tuned for more videos
about uh mission and renewal and
denominational